Finding aid for the Bonnie Cashin Collection of Fashion, Theater, and Film Costume Design LSC.0440
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Designs for Events / Non-Commercial Collections, 1953 - 1981; 65 folders
  - "Bonnie Cashin's Paper Route to Fashion", 1953 - January 7, 1972; 11 oversize boxes and 1 folder
    - Documents regarding proposed partnership between Cashin and American Can Company for paper clothing and home decor., ca. 1980 - 1981; 22 pages (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - Presentation to American Can Company regarding paper designs for home decor., January 16, 1981; 89 pages (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - Knit paper samples, with notations regarding length of time to create each sample., ca. 1967; 3 swatches (Box 175, Folder 1)
    - Prototypes of Cashin's paper slippers., ca. 1967; 2 items (Box 175, Folder 2)
    - Paper bag., undated, 1960s; 1 bag (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - Paper samples., ca. 1967; 11 items (some include multiple samples) (Box 175, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, samples, and costs of paper materials., ca. 1967; 19 pages (Box 175, Folder 5)
    - Brochures from paper manufacturers., 1960s; 7 brochures (Box 175, Folder 6)
    - Brochures from paper manufacturers., 1960s; 6 brochures (Box 175, Folder 7)
    - Paper hats with yarn ties designed by Cashin., 1967; 23 hats (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - Woven paper hats and glove designed by Cashin., 1967; 4 hats; 1 glove (Box 181, Folder 1)
    - Tufted paper Noh coat prototype, designed by Cashin., 1967; 1 coat (Box 303, Folder 1)
  - New York City Police: Uniforms, February 22, 1978; 1 folder
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of uniform designs for New York City police officers. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Memo and Cashin's illustrations of proposed uniform design., February 22, 1978; 5 pages (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Opera Costume for Aida, February 25, 1980; 1 folder
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's costume design for "Aida." All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Documents regarding Lincoln Center's "An International Salute to Opera: A Benefit for Writers and Artists for Peace in the Middle East.", February 25, 1980; 1 page (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - "Patternings", 1973 - 1974; 2 oversize boxes
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's "Patternings," a business plan to reinvigorate the home sewing market. All original illustrations by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Promotional ideas for "Patternings" presented by Ogilvy and Mather, Inc. for Sears, Roebuck and Co., 1973 - 1974; 9 pages (Box 197, Folder 1)
    - Storyboards and pattern for "Patternings" presented by Ogilvy and Mather, Inc. for Sears, Roebuck and Co., October 2, 1973 - August 14, 1974; 9 items (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - Ideas Regarding Train Travel, January 21, 1959 - 1970; 1 folder
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's writings and collected clippings regarding train travel. All original writings by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Notes and clippings regarding Cashin's ideas for train travel and related designs., January 21, 1959 - 1970; 26 pages (Box 202, Folder 4)
  - Hospital Gowns, ca. 1970s; 2 garments
    This subseries contains mock-up hospital gowns designed by Bonnie Cashin. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Mock-up hospital gowns designed by Cashin., ca. 1970s; 2 garments
- Professional Photographs of Bonnie Cashin, 1936 - 1995; 8 boxes and 7 folders
  This series contains publicity photographs and slides of Bonnie Cashin as well as photographs of her residential interiors taken for editorial purposes. The series is subdivided by location, including Cashin at home, in her design studios or showrooms, and at events. Some materials contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Press Events (Professional Photographs), 1974; 1 folder
    - Photographs of Cashin with Geraldine Fitzgerald in Cashin's studio, taken as publicity for "We, the Women," a CBS television special., February 1974; 11 photographs (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Publicity Photographs of Bonnie Cashin, 1936 - 1977; 19 folders
    This subseries contains photographs of Bonnie Cashin taken for publicity purposes. Some materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling her Adler and Adler ready-to-wear designs., 1936 - 1937; 11 photographs (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling her Adler and Adler ready-to-wear designs., 1936 - 1937; 12 photographs (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Color and black and white negatives of Cashin at work in Hollywood., 1943 - 1949; 13 negatives (Box 12, Folder 1)
      5 color negatives and 8 black and white negatives, 4" x 6".
    - Negatives of Cashin at work in Hollywood., 1943 - 1949; 8 negatives (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Black and white negatives, 8" x 10".
    - Photographs of Cashin in her Twentieth Century-Fox studio., 1947; 19 photographs (Box 12, Folder 3)
      2 images with multiple copies(15). Photographs later used for publicity release handled by Eleanor Lambert for BC's 1950 American Critics' Award, sponsored by Coty.
    - Photographs of Cashin, both social and professional, in her Twentieth Century-Fox studio., 1943 - 1949; 37 photographs (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of Cashin from "Marie Claire" magazine photo shoot; see also box 15, folder 3., 1948; 36 photographs (Box 12, Folder 5)
      See also Box 15, folder 3.
    - Photographs of Cashin with actresses reviewing costume designs for Twentieth Century-Fox films., 1943 - 1949; 5 photographs (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Cashin from "Marie Claire" magazine shoot; see also box 12, folder 5, 1948; 30 photographs (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Photograph of Cashin in her Twentieth Century-Fox studio., ca. 1944; 1 photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Oversize photographs of Cashin, mounted on board., ca. 1951 - 1953; 4 photographs (Box 18, Folder 2)
      photographer: Kay Bell
    - Portraits of Cashin., ca. 1951; 6 photographs (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Portraits of Cashin., ca. 1951 - 1953; 4 photographs (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Portraits of Cashin., ca. 1959; 6 photographs (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing hostess apron of her own design., ca. 1960; 3 photographs (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Slides: Cashin in her U.N. Plaza studio., ca. 1967; 9 slides (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Slides: Cashin and her U.N. Plaza apartment., 1969; 13 slides (Box 134, Folder 11)
    - Slides: Cashin in her U.N. Plaza apartment., ca. 1973 - 1977; 10 slides (Box 134, Folder 13)
    - Slides: Cashin in her studio., October 1977; 40 slides (Box 134, Folder 16)
  - Bonnie Cashin's Interiors (Professional Photographs)
    - Photographs of Cashin's apartment at 25 West 54th St., ca. 1955; 6 photographs (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Memo, photographs, negatives and color transparencies of Cashin's country house in Briarcliff Manor., June 1959; 24 pages (Box 60, Folder 2)
      photographer: Richard Averill Smith
    - Photographs of Cashin's apartment at 32 East 64th St., ca. 1959; 5 photographs (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Cashin's apartment at 32 East 64th St., ca. 1964; 4 photographs (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Photographs and color transparencies of Cashin's apartment at 32 East 64th St., ca. 1964; 4 items (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Photographs and contact sheets of Cashin's apartment and design studio at 860 U.N. Plaza., 1967; 13 photographs and contact sheets (Box 60, Folder 6)
      photographer: Bela Cseh for Boston Herald
    - Photographs of Cashin's apartment at 860 UN Plaza, 15G; includes letter from photographer, contact sheets and color transparencies., December 1976; 12 photographs (Box 60, Folder 7)
      photographer: Barbara Walz
    - Slides; Cashin's apartment East 64th St., NY, NY., ca. 1962; 8 slides (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Slides: Publicity photoshoot of Cashin's ready-to-wear sketches and swatches for Russell Taylor., 1979; 67 slides (Box 134, Folder 17)
  - Bonnie Cashin in Her Design Studios / Showrooms (Professional Photographs), ca. 1955 - 1977; 18 folders
    This subseries contains publicity photographs of Bonnie Cashin taken in her design studios or manufacturers showrooms. Some materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Photographs of Cashin in her design studio with manufacturer Philip Sills., ca. 1955; 5 pages (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Photographs of Cashin in the Coach workroom., ca. 1962; 22 photographs (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Cashin accepting "London Sunday Times Award" and visiting Ballantyne Cashmere headquarters., 1964; 4 photographs (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling and styling her paper clothing and accessory designs at her apartment and at a Sills and Co. showing., November 1967; 7 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing a tiger-print tunic of her own design, in her apartment., ca. 1967; 5 photographs (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing a suede tunic of her own design, in her studio., ca. 1968; 8 photographs (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing a Chinese worker's shirt, in her studio., Late 1960s; 3 photographs (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing windowpane-checked shirt of her own design, in her studio., Late 1960s; 8 photographs (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing a striped sweater of her own design, in her studio with cashmere swatches., Late 1960s; 8 photographs (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing instarsia sweater of her own design, in her studio., Late 1960s; 4 photographs (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Negatives of Cashin wearing a cashmere intarsia sweater of her own design against wall of leather scraps., ca. 1968; 1 page negatives; 21 photographs (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Photographs of Cashin in her studio., ca. 1972; 4 photographs (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of Cashin in houndstooth shirt of her own design, in her studio., ca. 1972; 20 photographs (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Photographic stills from "Young Designs in Mink" commercial shoot featuring Cashin, shot at her studio., 1975; 2 photographs (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing handknit sweaters of her own design, in her studio., 1977; 7 photographs (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing a leather coat of her own design on her shoulders, in her studio., ca. 1977; 2 photographs (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing funnel neck sweater and leopard print canvas pants of her own design, in her studio., 1977; 32 photographs (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Cashin featured in "Mirabella" with list of archival images published., January 1995; 2 items (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Bonnie Cashin at Home (Professional Photographs), ca. 1940 - 1977; 6 oversize boxes (46 folders)
    This subseries contains photographs and negatives of Bonnie Cashin in her residential interiors. Some materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Photographs of Cashin in organdy apron of her own design., ca. 1951; 8 photographs (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling "Siamese" pants and "Coolie" jacket of her own design., ca. 1951; 13 photographs (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Cashin in "Coolie" top and organdy dress of her own design., ca. 1951; 16 photographs (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling her collection of ethnic hats., August 1957; 77 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling her collection of ethnic hats., 1957; 7 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling her collection of ethnic hats and her designs including hostess and purse-pocket skirts., 1959; 61 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Cashin with visiting dignitaries from the Ivory Coast., 1962; 5 photographs (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing a cashmere intarsia sweater of her own design., ca. 1968; 4 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing a striped cashmere sweater of her own design., ca. 1968; 6 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Cashin wearing ponchos of her own design., ca. 1968; 2 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of Cashin in her U.N. Plaza apartment., Late 1960s; 6 photographs (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Cashin in a striped sweater of her own design, making funny faces., Late 1960s; 26 photographs (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Photographs of Bonnie Cashin., Late 1960s; 88 photographs (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Photographs of Cashin at U.N. Plaza., Late 1960s; 3 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling cashmere funnel neck sweater and Coach mail bag of her own design., ca. 1970; 15 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Cropped photographs of Cashin's face., ca. 1970; 64 pages of photographs, contact sheets, (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Cashin at home., ca. 1972; 4 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Cashin in front of her home library., ca. 1972; 15 pages of photographs, contact sheets (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling linen outfit of her own design., Mid 1970s; 7 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling ponchos of her own design., ca. 1977; 12 photographs (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Cashin., 1957 - 1977; 4 photographs (Box 292, Folder 7)
  - Bonnie Cashin at Events (Professional Photographs), 1950s - February 22, 1991; 3 oversize boxes and 2 folders
    This subseries contains photographs of Bonnie Cashin attending various events. Some materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Photographs of Cashin at fashion show with Gypsy Rose Lee., ca. 1955; 4 photographs (Box 61, Folder 7)
      photographer:Halley Erksine
    - Photographs of Cashin at Lord and Taylor., ca. 1957; 6 photographs (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Photographs of Cashin at various events wearing evening wear of her own design cut from Dorothy Liebes fabrics., 1950s; 5 photographs (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Photographs of Cashin at various events., 1950s; 25 photographs (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Photographs of Cashin at Mount Mary College., 1966; 4 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of Cashin., 1960s; 11 photographs (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of Cashin visiting London., 1966; 8 photographs (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Cashin in London at the "Time-Life" reception celebrating an exhibition of her ready-to-wear illustrations., 1966; 40 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Cashin in New York City., 1970s; 3 photographs (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Cashin at a Cleveland fashion show., 1974; 5 photographs (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Cashin modeling a fur tunic of her own design for H.B.A. Fur Corp., for acceptance of 1976 Fur Awards., 5 pages of photographs, contact sheets, and negatives (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of Cashin at unknown event., May 5, 1979; 3 photographs (Box 66, Folder 10)
- Personal Photographs, ca. 1912 - 1977; 9 oversize boxes and 6 folders
  This series contains personal photographs and slides of Bonnie Cashin as well as her friends and family. The series is particularly rich in photographs of or by Cashin while traveling. The series is subdivided by travel, family and friends, and parties as well as Cashin alone in her design studios or showrooms, at events, and at home. All materials contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Bonnie Cashin at Home (Personal Photographs), ca. 1937 - 1965; 24 folders
    - Slides: Cashin during her Hollywood period (1941-1949) and after; slides 10 - 20 of Mrs. Elmer G. Plummer., ca. 1940 - 1965; 23 slides (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Slides; Cashin's residential interiors and Cashin at her home in Briarcliff Manor., ca. 1961; 10 slides (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Negatives of Cashin, marked "old misc.", ca. 1937; 3 negatives (Box 289, Folder 2)
    - Negatives of Cashin in her home studio., ca. 1960; 3 rows of negatives (Box 289, Folder 4)
    - Negatives marked "@ Forest Hills.", ca. 1957 - 1960; 6 negatives (Box 289, Folder 6)
    - Negatives of Cashin and family at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1956; 8 rows of negatives (Box 289, Folder 9)
    - Negatives of Bonnie Cashin and family at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1956; 7 rows of negatives (Box 289, Folder 10)
    - Negatives of Bonnie Cashin at her easel, at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 4 rows of negatives (Box 289, Folder 11)
    - Negatives of Cashin modeling hats at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 5 rows of negatives (Box 289, Folder 12)
    - Negatives of Cashin modeling hats at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 8 rows of negatives (Box 289, Folder 13)
    - Negatives of Cashin and family at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 5 rows of negatives (Box 289, Folder 14)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., Summer 1957; 29 negatives (Box 289, Folder 16)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 15 negatives (Box 289, Folder 17)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor; sent from Dorothy Liebes to Eunice Cashin., 1957; 3 negatives (Box 289, Folder 18)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 5 negatives (Box 289, Folder 19)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 8 negatives (Box 289, Folder 20)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 26 negatives (Box 289, Folder 21)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 22 negatives (Box 289, Folder 22)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 28 negatives (Box 289, Folder 23)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 35 negatives (Box 289, Folder 24)
    - Negatives of Cashin with family and friends at her home in Briarcliff Manor., 1957; 6 rows of negatives (Box 289, Folder 25)
    - Photographs of Cashin., ca. 1955 - 1957; 12 photographs (Box 290, Folder 1)
    - Negatives marked "N.Y. apartment misc.", ca. 1957; 4 negatives (Box 290, Folder 12)
    - Negatives and photographs marked "E.C.; Stores; model; 32 East 64th.", January 1959; 22 negatives; 4 photographs (Box 290, Folder 26)
  - Bonnie Cashin in Her Design Studios / Showrooms (Personal Photographs), 1949 - 1977; 9 folders
    This subseries contains publicity of Bonnie Cashin taken in her design studios or manufacturers showrooms. Some materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Negatives and photographs of Cashin with friends including setting up a Dorothy Liebes loom at her country house, hosting parties, and attending the Brussell's Worlds Fair., 1958; 19 pages; 23 photographs (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Slides: Cashin in her studio, apartment, and Sills and Co. showroom., April - November 1967; 6 slides (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Slides: Cashin in her studio and Sills and Co. showroom., January 1968; 3 slides (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Slides: Cashin in her studio., March 1968; 9 slides (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Slides: Cashin in her studio and Sills and Co. showroom., May 1968; 9 slides (Box 134, Folder 9)
    - Slides: Cashin in her studio., ca. 1972; 3 slides (Box 134, Folder 12)
    - Slides: private showing in Cashin's studio., May 1976; 11 slides (Box 134, Folder 14)
    - Slides: Cashin in her studio., May 1977; 8 slides (Box 134, Folder 15)
    - Negatives of Cashin in her Twentieth Century-Fox studio., 1949; 13 negatives (Box 289, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Museum Events; Non-Fashion (Personal Photographs), 1975 - 1976; 1 folder
    - Documents regarding Cashin's holographic portrait for UNICEF fundraising., October 15, 1975 - April 6, 1976; 10 pages (Box 204, Folder 3)
  - Press Events (Personal Photographs), 1957; 1 folder
    - Negatives marked "Terrace - press group.", 1957; 6 negatives (Box 290, Folder 8)
  - Family and Friends, 1912 - Ca. 1995; 22 folders
    This subseries contains photographs of Bonnie Cashin's family and friends. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Black and white photographs of Cashin and friends., ca. 1912-1931; 46 photographs (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Black and white photographs of Cashin's friends and relatives., 1912-1925; 20 photographs (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Black and white photographs of Cashin's Aunt Ruth., ca. 1925; 4 photographs (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of and by Robert Sterner (Cashin's husband) and Eunice Cashin (Cashin's mother)., ca. 1940; 3 photographs (Box 11, Folder 2)